<resources>
    <string name="app_name">IPU Syllabus</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">Main2Activity</string>

    <string name="instructionssem1.1">1. Question No. 1 should be compulsory and cover the entire syllabus. This question should have objective
        or short answer type questions. It should be of 25 marks.</string>
    <string name="instructionssem1.2">2. Apart from Question No. 1, rest of the paper shall consist of four units as per the syllabus. Every unit
        should have two questions. However, student may be asked to attempt only 1 question from each unit.
        Each question should be of 12.5 marks.</string>
    <string name="content1.1">UNIT- I\n
        Successive differentiation: Leibnitz theorem for nth derivative (without proof). Infinite series: Convergence and
divergence of infinite series, positive terms infinite series, necessary condition, comparison test (Limit test),
D’Alembert ratio test, Integral Test, Cauchy’s root test, Raabe’s test and Logarithmic test(without proof).
Alternating series, Leibnitz test, conditional and absolutely convergence. Taylor’s and Maclaurin’s
expansion(without proof) of function ( ex, log(1+x), cos x , sin x) with remainder terms ,Taylor’s and
Maclaurin’s series, Error and approximation.</string>
    <string name="content1.2">UNIT- II\n
        Asymptotes to Cartesian curves. Radius of curvature and curve tracing for Cartesian, parametric and polar
curves. Integration: integration using reduction formula for sin, cos and combination of sin and cos. Application of integration : Area under the curve, length
of the curve, volumes and surface area of solids of revolution about axis only .Gamma and Beta functions.</string>
    <string name="content1.3">UNIT- III\n
Matrices: Orthogonal matrix, Hermitian matrix, Skew-Hermitian matrix and Unitary matrix. Inverse of matrix
by Gauss-Jordan Method (without proof). Rank of matrix by echelon and Normal (canonical) form. Linear
dependence and linear independence of vectors. Consistency and inconsistency of linear system of
homogeneous and non homogeneous equations . Eigen values and Eigen vectors. Properties of Eigen values
(without proof). Cayley-Hamilton theorem (without proof). Diagonlization of matrix. Quadratic form, reduction
of quadratic form to canonical form.</string>
    <string name="content1.4">UNIT-IV\n
        Ordinary differential equations: First order linear differential equations, Leibnitz and Bernaulli’s equation. Exact
differential equations , Equations reducible to exact differential equations. Linear differential equation of higher
order with constant coefficients, Homogeneous and non homogeneous differential equations reducible to linear
differential equations with constant coefficients. Method of variation of parameters. Bessel’s and Legendre’s
equations (without series solutions), Bessel’s and Legendre’s functions and their properties.</string>
    <string name="content2.1">UNIT I\n
        Interference: Introduction, Interference due to division of wave front: Fresnel’s Biprism, Interference due to
division of amplitude: wedge shaped film, Newton’s rings.\n
        Diffraction: Introduction, Difference between Fresnel and Fraunhofer diffraction, Single slit diffraction,
Transmission diffraction grating, Absent spectra.</string>
    <string name="content2.2">UNIT II\n
        Polarization: Introduction, Uniaxial crystals, Double refraction, Nicol prism, Quarter and half wave plates,
Theory of production of plane, circularly and elliptically polarized lights, Specific rotation, Laurents half shade
polarimeter.\n
        Laser: Spontaneous and stimulated emissions, Einstein’s coefficients, Laser and its principle, He-Ne laser.\n
Fibre optics: Introduction, Single mode fibre, Step index and graded index multimode fibres,
Acceptance angle and numerical aperture.</string>
    <string name="content2.3">UNIT III\n
        Theory of Relativity: Introduction, Frame of reference, Galilean transformation, Michelson-Morley
experiment, Postulates of special theory of relativity, Lorentz transformations, Length contraction, Time
dilation, Mass energy relation.\n
        Ultrasonics: Introduction, Production of ultrasonics by magnetostriction and Piezoelectric methods,
Applications.</string>
    <string name="content2.4">UNIT IV\n
        Nuclear Physics: Introduction, Radioactivity, Alpha decay, Beta decay, Gamma decay, Q value, Threshold
energy, Nuclear reactions, Nuclear fission: Liquid drop model, Nuclear fusion, Particle accelerators: Linear
accelerator, Cyclotron, Radiation detectors: Ionization chamber, Geiger Mueller Counter.</string>
    <string name="content3.1">UNIT-I\n
        Introduction:\n
        Introduction of Manufacturing processes and their classification, Basic Metals and Alloys :
Properties and Applications. Properties of Materials: Strength, elasticity, stiffness, malleability, ductility,
brittleness, toughness and hardness. Ferrous Materials: Carbon steels, its classification based on % carbon as
low, mild, medium and high carbon steel, its properties and applications. Wrought iron. Cast iron. Alloy steels:
stainless steel, tool steel. Elementary introduction to Heat- treatment of carbon steels: annealing, normalizing,
quenching and tempering and case- hardening.\n
        Non-Ferrous metals and alloys: Properties and uses of various non-ferrous metals and alloys and its composition
such as Cu-alloys: Brass, Bronze, Al-alloys such as Duralumin.\n
        Casting Processes:\n
        Principles of metal casting, Pattern materials, types and allowance, composition and properties of moulding
sand, foundry tools, concept of cores and core print, elements of gating system, description and operation of
cupola, special casting processes e.g. die-casting; permanent mould casting; centrifugal casting; investment
casting; casting defects.</string>
    <string name="content3.2">UNIT-II\n
Smithy and Forging:\n
        Hot working and cold working, Forging tools and equipments, Forging operations, Forging types: Smith
forging, Drop forging, Press forging, Machine forging; Forging defects; Extrusion, wire drawing, swaging.\n
Bench Work and Fitting:\n
        Fitting shop tools, operation: Fitting; sawing; chipping; thread cutting (with taps and dies);
Marking and marking tools.</string>
    <string name="content3.3">UNIT-III\n
        Metal joining: Welding principles, classification of welding techniques, Oxyacetylene Gas welding, equipment
and field of application, Arc-welding, metal arc, Carbon arc welding, submerged arc welding and atomic
hydrogen welding, TIG and MIG welding, Electric resistance welding: spot; seam; flash; butt and percussion
welding, Flux: composition; properties and function, Electrodes, Types of joints and edge preparation, Brazing
and soldering, welding defects.
</string>
    <string name="content3.4">UNIT-IV\n
        Sheet Metal Work:\n
        Tools and equipments used in sheet metal work, metals used for sheets, standard specification for sheets, Types
of sheet metal operations: shearing, drawing, bending. Other operations like spinning, stretch forming,
embossing and coining.\n
        Powder Metallurgy: Introduction of powder metallurgy process: powder production, blending, compaction,
sintering.</string>
    <string name="content4.1">UNIT – I: DC Circuits\n
        Introduction of Circuit parameters and energy sources (Dependent and Independent), Mesh and Nodal Analysis,
Superposition, Thevenin’s, Norton’s, Reciprocity, Maximum Power Transfer and Millman’s Theorems, Star-
Delta Transformation and their Applications to the Analysis of DC circuits.</string>
    <string name="content4.2">UNIT – II: A.C.Circuits\n
        A.C. Fundamentals, Phasor representation, Steady State Response of Series and Parallel R-L, R-C and R-L-C
circuits using j-notation, Series and Parallel resonance of RLC Circuits, Quality factor, Bandwidth, Complex
Power, Introduction to balanced 3-phase circuits with Star- Delta Connections.</string>
    <string name="content4.3">UNIT – III: Measuring Instruments\n
        Basics of measuring instruments and their types ,Working principles and applications of moving coil, moving
iron (ammeter and voltmeter) and Extension of their ranges, dynamometer- type Wattmeter , induction-type
Energy Meter , Two-wattmeter method for the measurement of power in three phase circuits, Introduction to
digital voltmeter, digital Multimeter and Electronic Energy Meter.</string>
    <string name="content4.4">UNIT – IV: Transformer and Rotating Machines\n
        Fundamentals of Magnetic Circuits, Hysteresis and Eddy current losses, working principle, equivalent circuit,
efficiency and voltage regulation of single phase transformer and its applications. Introduction to DC and
Induction motors (both three phase and single phase), Stepper Motor and Permanent Magnet Brushless DC
Motor.</string>
    <string name="content5.1">UNIT-I\n
        Five Component Model of a Computer, System and Application software ( introduction ) storage devices ,
primary (RAM, ROM, PROM, EPROM, cache ) Memory and secondary (magnetic tape, hard disk, Compact
disks) memory , peripheral devices , printers.</string>
    <string name="content5.2">UNIT-II\n
        Operating Systems: DOS Internal, External commands, Windows ( 2000 and NT) , Overview of architecture of
Windows, tools and system utilities including registry , partitioning of hard disk , Overview of Linux
architecture , File system , file and permissions , concept of user and group , installation of rpm and deb based
packages.</string>
    <string name="content5.3">UNIT-III\n
        Basics of programming through flow chart , Networking Basics - Uses of a network and Common types of
networks , Network topologies and protocols , Network media and hardware , Overview of Database
Management System.</string>
    <string name="content5.4">UNIT-IV\n
        Libre / Open Office Writer : Editing and Reviewing, Drawing, Tables, Graphs, Templates\n
        Libre / Open Office Calc : Worksheet Management , Formulas, Functions, Charts\n
        Libre / Open Office Impress: designing powerful power-point presentation</string>
   <string name="content6">Non-University Examination Scheme (NUES)\n
       Note: There will be no End-Term External University Examination. Marks are to be given on the basis of two
internal sessional test of 30 marks each and one final Viva-voce project report Examination of 40 marks.</string>
    <string name="content6.1">UNIT-1: Introduction to Value Education\n
        1. Understanding the need, basic guidelines, content and process for value education.\n
        2. Basic Human Aspirations: Prosperity and happiness\n
        3. Methods to fulfil the human aspirations – understanding and living in harmony at various levels.\n
        4. Practice Session – 1.</string>
    <string name="content6.2">UNIT-2: Harmony in the Human Being\n
        1. Co-existence of the sentient “I” and the material body – understanding their needs – Happiness and
Conveniences.\n
        2. Understanding the Harmony of “I” with the body – Correct appraisal of physical needs and the meaning of
prosperity.\n
        3. Programme to ensure harmony of “I” and Body-Mental and Physical health and happiness.\n
        4. Harmony in family and society: Understanding Human-human relationship in terms of mutual trust and
respect.\n
        5. Understanding society and nation as extensions of family and society respectively.\n
        6. Practice Session – 02</string>
    <string name="content6.3">UNIT-3: Basics of Professional Ethics\n
        1. Ethical Human Conduct – based on acceptance of basic human values.\n
        2. Humanistic Constitution and universal human order – skills, sincerity and fidelity.\n
        3. To identify the scope and characteristics of people – friendly and eco-friendly production system,
Technologies and management systems.\n
        4. Practice Session – 03.</string>
    <string name="content6.4">UNIT-4: Professional Ethics in practice\n
        1. Profession and Professionalism – Professional Accountability, Roles of a professional, Ethics and image
of profession.\n
        2. Engineering Profession and Ethics - Technology and society, Ethical obligations of Engineering
professionals, Roles of Engineers in industry, society, nation and the world.\n
        3. Professional Responsibilities – Collegiality, Loyalty, Confidentiality, Conflict of Interest, Whistle
Blowing.\n
        4. Practice Session – 04</string>
    <string name="content7.1">Unit –I\n
        Partial differentiation and its Applications: Partial derivatives of first and second order. Euler’s theorem for
homogeneous functions (without proof). Derivatives of Implicit Functions, total derivatives. Change of
variables. Jacobian. Taylor’s theorem for function of two variables(without proof). Error and approximation.
Extreme values of function of several variables(maxima ,minima, saddle points). Lagrange method of
undetermined multipliers. Partial differential equations: Formulation, solution of first order equations,
Lagranges equations, Charpit’s method.</string>
    <string name="content7.2">Unit-II\n
Laplace Transformation: Definition, Laplace transformation of basic functions , existence condition for Laplace
transformation, Properties of Laplace transformation(Linearity, scaling and shifting). Unit step function,
Impulse Function, Periodic Functions. Laplace transformation of derivatives, Laplace transformation of
integrals, differentiation of transforms, Integration of transforms, Convolution theorem ,inverse Laplace
transformation. Solution of ordinary Differential equations.</string>
    <string name="content7.3">Unit-III\n
        Complex Function: Definition, Derivatives, Analytic function, Cauchy’s Riemann equation (without proof).
Conformal and bilinear mappings, Complex Integration: Complex Line integration, Cauchy’s integral theorem
and integral formula(without proof). Zeros and Singularities, Taylor’s and Laurent’s series (without proof).
Residues, Residue theorem (without proof). Evaluation of real definite integrals: Integration around the unit
circle, Integration around a small semi circle and integration around rectangular contours.</string>
    <string name="content7.4">Unit-IV\n
        Multiple integrals: Double integrals, Change of order of integration, Triple integrals. Vector Calculus: Scalar
and vector functions, Gradient, Divergence and curl. Directional derivatives, Line Integrals. Surface integrals,
volume integrals. Green’s theorem, Stoke’s theorem and Gauss divergence theorem (without proof).</string>
    <string name="content8.1">UNIT I\n
Electromagnetic Theory : Gradient, Divergence, Curl, Gauss’ law, Ampere’s Law, Continuity equation,
Maxwell’s equations (differential and integral forms), Significance of Maxwell’s equations, Poynting Theorem,
Electromagnetic wave propagation in dielectrics and conductors.</string>
    <string name="content8.2">UNIT II\n
        Statistical Physics: Black body radiation, Planck\'s radiation formula, Wien\'s and Rayleigh-Jeans Laws,
Distribution laws: Qualitative features of Maxwell-Boltzmann, Bose-Einstein and Fermi-Dirac statistics and their
comparison (without derivation).\n
        Quantum Mechanics: Postulates of Quantum mechanics, de-Broglie hypothesis, Davisson Germer experiment,
Wave function and its physical significance, Wave Packet, Phase and group velocities, Uncertainty principle,
Schrodinger equation for free particle, Time dependent Schrodinger equation, Particle in a box (1-D).</string>
    <string name="content8.3">UNIT III\n
        Crystal Structure: Types of solids, Unit cell, Types of crystals, Translation vectors, Lattice planes, Miller
indices, Simple crystal structures, Interplaner spacing, Crystal structure analysis: Bragg’s law, Laue method,
Point defects: Schottcky and Frankel defects.</string>
    <string name="content8.4">UNIT IV\n
        Band Theory of Solids: Introduction, Kronig-Penney model: E-k diagram, Effective mass of an electron,
Intrinsic semiconductors: Electron concentration in conduction band, Hole concentration in valence band,
Extrinsic semiconductor: p-type and n-type semiconductors, Fermi level, Hall Effect: Hall voltage and Hall
coefficient.</string>
    <string name="content9.1">UNIT-I\n
        Evaluation Of Electronics: Introduction and Application Of Electronics, Energy Band Theory Of Crystals,
Energy Band Structures In Metals, Semiconductors And Insulators, Theory Of Semiconductors: Classification
Of Semiconductors, Conductivity Of Semiconductors, Carrier Concentration In Intrinsic and Extrinsic
Semiconductors, Properties Of Intrinsic And Extrinsic Semiconductors, Variation In Semiconductors
Parameters With Temperature, Fermi-Dirac Function, Fermi Level In A Semiconductor Having Impurities,
Band Structure Of Open-Circuited P-N Junction, Drift And Diffusion Currents, Carrier Life Time, Continuity
Equation (Elementary Treatment Only).</string>
    <string name="content9.2">UNIT – II\n
Theory of p-n junction Diode: Diode Current Equation, Diode Resistance, Transition Capacitance, Diffusion
Capacitance, (Elementary treatment only), Effect of Temperature on p-n Junction Diode, Switching
Characteristics, Piecewise Linear Model, Special Diodes: Zener Diode, Varactor Diode, Tunnel Diode,
Photodiode, Light Emitting Diodes, Schottky Barrier Diode, Applications of Diodes: Half-Wave Diode
Rectifier, Full-Wave Rectifier, Clippers and Clampers (Elementary treatment only).</string>
    <string name="content9.3">Unit – III\n
        Bipolar junction transistor: Introduction of transistor, construction, transistor operations, BJT characteristics,
load line, operating point, leakage currents, saturation and cut off mode of operations, Eber-moll’s model.</string>
    <string name="content9.4">Unit – IV\n
        Application of BJT: CB, CE, CC configurations, hybrid model for transistor at low frequencies, Introduction to
FETs and MOSFETs.\n
        Fundamentals of digital electronics: Digital and analog signals, number systems, Boolean algebra, logic gates
with simple applications, logic gates, karnaugh maps.</string>
    <string name="content10.1">UNIT I\n
        Concept of algorithms, Flow Charts, Overview of the compiler ( preferably GCC) , Assembler, linker and
loader , Structure of a simple Hello World Program in C ,Overview of compilation and execution process in an
IDE ( preferably Code Block).</string>
    <string name="content10.2">UNIT II\n
        Programming using C: Preprocessor Directive, C primitive input output using get char and put char , simple I/O
Function calls from library , data type in C including enumeration , arithmetic, relational and logical operations,
conditional executing using if, else, switch and break .Concept of loops , for, while and do-while , Storage
Classes: Auto, Register, Static and Extern.</string>
    <string name="content10.3">UNIT III\n
        Arrays (one and two dimensional), 2-d arrays used in matrix computation. Concept of Sub-programming,
functions. Parameter transmission schemes i.e. call by value and call by reference, Pointers, relationship
between array and pointer, Argument passing using pointers, Array of pointer, passing arrays as arguments</string>
    <string name="content10.4">UNIT IV\n
        Structure and unions , Strings and C string library, File Handling in C Using File Pointers,fopen( ), fclose(),Input and Output using file pointers, Character Input and Output with Files , String Input / Output Functions ,
Formatted Input / Output Functions,Block Input / Output Functions, Sequential Vs Random Access Files ,
Positioning the File Pointer</string>
</resources>
